NISHIPAL Y. RANA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

in nishipalsinhrana

nishipalrana

Ahmedabad, India +91 8980672129 nishipalrana@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

As an experienced Full Stack developer with 2.5 years of expertise in React, Node.js, REST API, Microservices, Spring framework, and relational database, I possess strong analytical and technical skills. With a solid background in banking and financial markets and automotive industry, I possess excellent leadership abilities and am comfortable working independently or as part of a team. My technical expertise, combined with my collaborative approach, enables me to deliver results and add value to any project.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, Redux, TypeScript, Azure, Node.js, Fauna DB, REST API, Microservices, Spring Cloud, Jest & React Testing Library, SQL(Oracle), HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Jenkins, Pivotal Cloud.

EDUCATION

A. D. Patel Institute of Technology, Anand, Gujarat

2016-2020

B.E. in Electrical Engineering | CGPA: 8.92

Adarsh Mahavidyalaya, Gandhidham, Gujarat

2014-2016

GSEB | HSC Science Stream | Percentage: 75.54%

Modern School, Gandhidham, Gujarat

2013 - 2014

GSEB | SSC | Percentage: 84.67%

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer DILX LLP, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

Nov, 2022 - Present

- · Worked extensively on optimizing GraphQL queries to improve performance for the end user by ~25 %.
- Implemented a critical feature to save and collate logs in a NoSQL database using unique parameters, resulting in significant efficiency improvements and time savings for issue identification.
- Proficient in building robust APIs, and optimizing data management using MongoDB, GraphQL, and Apollo GraphQL.
- Skilled in TypeScript and React.js for seamless front-end development.
- Experienced in developing and testing high-performance web apps using **Jest**.
- Knowledgeable in implementing and deploying apps for optimal performance and scalability on Azure DevOps, Azure Kubernetes Service, and Kubernetes.
- Strong problem-solving skills and technical expertise.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer/Analyst

Feb, 2021 - Oct, 2022

CAPGEMINI TECHNOLOGY SERVICES, Pune, Maharashtra

- Developed **React** web applications using Single-Spa framework which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually.
- Single handedly developed and implemented **Spring Cloud Gateway** and **Discovery Client** for **20+ microservices**.
- Written unit test cases for all modules in the project using **Jest** and **React Testing Library (RTL)** with the overall code coverage greater than **90%**.
- Experience with source version control systems such as **GIT**, continuous integration tools like **Jenkins**, static code analysis tools like **Sonar** and cloud platform like **Pivotal Cloud Foundry**.
- Updated code bases to modern development standards, conforming to the client-defined Quality Gates and Vulnerability Scanning tools.
- Awards & Recognition:-
- Star of the Month award for H2, 2021 (Banking & Capital Markets).
- Pat on Back award for Q2, 2021 (Banking & Capital Markets).

Frontend Developer (Freelancing)

Sep, 2022 - Oct, 2022

INVOSHINE SOFTWARE SOLUTIONS PRIVATE LIMITED

• Developed user-friendly web application in **React** for an Insurance company based out of USA.

Test Engineer, Infotainment & Telematics MORRIS GARAGES, Halol, Gujarat

Oct, 2020 - Jan, 2021

- Created comprehensive test plans, test scripts and use cases to support testing objectives.
- Reviewed, evaluated and identified requirements for testability.
- Analyzed test results and prepared system-level evaluation reports to verify and validate system
 performance.
- Tested hardware and software within the sandbox environment before the production release.
- Created plans for test method validation using research or field observations.

ACHIEVEMENTS & VOLUNTEERING

- 2nd Runner Up at **District Youth Parliament 2019** organized by **Govt. of India**.
- Represented Anand District at State Youth Parliament 2019 organized Ministry of Youth Affairs and Sports, Govt. of India.
- Winner of G.K. Quiz at AMUL VOLCANO, 2020.
- Mentored college students on Web Development for Q-Impacts Hackathon organized by Digital Page and supported by Capgemini.
- Technical Instructor for SQL Masterclass on **BitClass** App with over **3400+** registered students and a **4.5/5** rating.

HOBBIES

Philately, Numismatics, Badminton, Reading